Dwayne Washington

1515 Manning Avenue, Unit 11 Los Angeles, CA 90024 (310) 746-8795 dwash@xplosv.com

PROFILE

Designer and developer with an excellent eye for detail, solid communication skills, and experience in fast-paced, agile development environments. Enjoys building useful, usable, well-constructed sites and applications, solving problems, working with a team and constantly learning.

RESOURCES

UX/UI Portfolio: http://dwaynewashington.crevado.com

Website: http://dwaynewashington.com

GitHub: https://github.com/hoopmechanic

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dwayne-washington-UX-UI-Dev/

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UX/UI and Full Stack Development Consultant

4/2015 - present

Washington Apps, Inc.

Drupal Developer for Timing Excellence, LLC

Created and deployed a full-featured sports event timing online registration web application. Features include a listing of upcoming registered events, completed events with timed results and an online registration system.

- Built site on the Drupal content management system (CMS).
- Created custom content types and implemented Panels, Blocks and Views to customize the design of the site.
- Modified jQuery and Ajax on existing template to improve user interfaces.
- Maintained installation with module and security updates.

UX/UI Design Consultant for Facepop Company, LLC

Worked as design consultant for start-up to refactor interface for mobile application.

- Met with stakeholders, designers and developers to review existing user experience documentation and develop a complete understanding of requirements.
- Created sketches and high fidelity wireframes that met the client's needs and vision.

Lead Drupal and React Frontend Development Consultant for UnifyMe.tv

Created and deployed an on-demand media streaming site on the Drupal content management system platform and developed a programmed media streaming site with React.js.

- Built a custom template for the on-demand site featuring jQuery and Ajax.
- Developed a custom client management data component in Views to update user data, streaming media and image gallery resources.
- Managed a Drupal development consultant to create a custom module that modified the Stripe payment module to accept payments and issue credits for access to streaming media resources.
- Built a programmed streaming site with React.js and implemented the Wowza Player Javascript API for clients to view content.
- Configured the Wowza Streaming server to deliver content using the Wowza Streaming Engine REST API service.

Dwayne Washington

1515 Manning Avenue, Unit 11 Los Angeles, CA 90024 (310) 746-8795 dwash@xplosv.com

Senior UX/UI Designer and IA Specialist

University of California Los Angeles Student Affairs Information Technology 5/2012 - 4/2015

Promoted to the Student Affairs Information Technology (SAIT) department to work with stakeholders and the development team on a variety of high priority and deadline sensitive projects. Collaborated with an outside consultant to advise on IA. Developed new approaches to complex interface and UX problems, created user-focused interfaces and refactored designs for the UCLA Online Registration and Student Enrollment Management System. Provided consulting for a variety of interdepartmental projects that included the development of UI interfaces for web CMS, mobile web, tablet, and mobile applications (iOS).

- Used Omnigraffle, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator and Axure RP to create a variety of user-focused design elements that improved the user experience for the UCLA Registration and Student Enrollment Management System applications.
- Worked as lead designer responsible for managing the creation of personas, process workflows, user workflows, sketches, conceptual wireframes, high fidelity designs and live prototypes to present to stakeholders in UCLA's UIT, ITS and SAIT departments.
- Worked closely with stakeholders, internal department designers and developers to determine the requirements and define interface.
- Organized and implemented multiple user tests and observations.
- Presented designs in the form of presentations, prototypes, and coding specifications.
- Created high fidelity wireframes and other deliverables based on the UCLA brand identity for the development team.
- Used HTML and CSS to incorporate wireframe designs in development environment.
- Migrated UCLA Recreation ASP.net web site to Expression Engine content management system and created custom template based on UCLA brand identity.

Web Designer/UI Specialist

10/2007 - 5/2012

University of California Los Angeles Cultural and Recreation Affairs

Worked as a web design specialist to refactor and update a variety of fitness and health-based web sites. Promoted to work on Bridges 2 Health (B2H) project, a multilayered recreation management web application. Collaborated with technology professionals from UC Berkeley, UC Davis, UCLA and other outside development vendors.

- Organized meetings with stakeholders to refactor the design requirements for the B2H project.
- Created and presented sketches, conceptual wireframes, high fidelity designs for stakeholder review and approval.
- Worked with developers in ASP.net environment to implement UI for Bridges 2 Health (B2H) project.
- Created and implemented style guide for B2H developers.
- Planned, created and launched iWorkout, a user activity management site for the FITWELL department.
- Provided general support and wrote SQL scripts to create annual reports for iWorkout from MSSQL data source.
- Redesigned and maintained a host of existing Recreation sites.

Lab Director 12/1996 – 6/2004

University of California Los Angeles 7 Office of Instructional Development Instructional Multimedia Production Lab (Student Post-Production Facility)

Designed, built and managed a post-production facility that served over 15 faculty and 2,500 students annually for the Office of Instruction Development. This facility provided media production services for students outside of the UCLA Film and Television department. This position required collaboration with faculty to develop media-based curriculum projects as student assignments that included the production and manipulation of various types of media: photos, video and audio.

- Evaluated and purchased computer equipment and supplies for facility.
- Installed and maintained over 50 Apple and PC post-production and graphic workstations as well as specialty stations for the collection of various forms of media.
- Recruited, hired and trained a part-time student-based lab consultant team, a full-time assistant and a full-time lab technician.
- Prepared detailed, accurate annual budgets and successfully operated within projections.
- Designed multimedia training courses and procedural manuals for staff and faculty that included detailed instructions on workflows and the use of post-production and graphic software.
- Developed and implemented a marketing plan to promote the services of the lab to faculty in all academic
 departments that included organized special events, demonstrations and contests.
- Worked with Apple and Adobe to beta test post-production and graphic software applications including Final Cut Pro.

Dwayne Washington

1515 Manning Avenue, Unit 11 Los Angeles, CA 90024 (310) 746-8795 dwash@xplosv.com

EDUCATION

Moviola

Avid Finishing on Media Composer, 2001

University of California Los Angeles

Bachelor of Arts, Economics 1987

University of California Los Angeles Extension

User Experience: Mobile First, 2015 User Experience II Course, 2012 User Experience I Course, 2012

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE

- Expert knowledge of Adobe Photoshop, including PSD to HTML conversion
- Bootstrap, MVC, GIT and Rapid prototyping
- Drupal, WordPress, DNN, Joomla and Expression Engine
- XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and REST API
- React, React Native, Mongo, Express, Node.js, Redux and Webpack
- Firebase, Yeoman, AWS, Mern, Meteor, Digital Ocean and Heruko
- JEST and Jasmine
- Experience with FaceBook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram and other social media web site
- Server integration

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

- Sketch, Zeplin, InVision, Principle, Marvel, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle
- Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign, Acrobat Professional
- Apple Final Cut Pro Studio, Avid Xpress Pro, Davinci Resolve and Adobe After Effects
- MacOS, Windows, Ubuntu, Debian and Red Hat
- Microsoft Office

EXTRACURRICULAR

- Finalist in 1987 NCAA Outdoor Track and Field Championship Meet
- DrupalCon Conference attendee
- PhotoshopWorld Conference attendee
- Lifetime member of the UCLA Alumni Association
- Organized and led a nonprofit aimed at teaching technology to inner-city youth.
- Coach and mentor for basketball, track and cross country teams at local private and public high schools.